Nicole Aldurien

Software Engineer

Atlanta, GA | nicole.aldurien@gmail.com

nicole-aldurien.surge.sh | github.com/nicolealdurien | linkedin.com/in/nicolealdurien

Creative software engineer with the ability to pick up new languages and technologies as needed. Prior to changing careers, I worked as a certified medical laboratory scientist for Emory University Hospital, where I conducted immunohematological testing to ensure safe administration of blood and bone marrow transplants to inpatients and outpatients at Georgia's largest academic medical center.

Software Development Skills

 Debugging, JavaScript, Python, Node.js, React, Express, Redux, RESTful API, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Bootstrap, Flexbox, AWS, React Native, HTML, CSS

Education

DigitalCrafts | Certificate in Software Engineering | Atlanta, GA

February 2021 - present

 Software engineering training program covering full-stack development including (but not limited to) JavaScript and Python, with an emphasis on cutting-edge frameworks like React/Redux and server-side technologies including Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL.

Texas State University | B.S. in Clinical Laboratory Science | San Marcos, TX | STEM GPA: 4.0

degree conferred August 2014

Software Development Portfolio

wasteNOT | wastenotorg.herokuapp.com | github.com/nicolealdurien/wasteNOT

April 2021

- Member of a 3-person distributed development team on a modified-follow-the-sun schedule (due to one team member's
 family commitments), building a website that allows a theoretical charity to facilitate donation of excess unsold food from
 restaurants to food banks and soup kitchens.
- Primary responsibilities included implementing a fully mobile-responsive layout, schema design for user, admin, donation, and food bank tables in Postgres, creating user registration functionality with password encryption, and creating food bank information page and location page.
- Built with Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, Mustache, HTML, and CSS.

Catch Up Over Coffee | catch-up-over-coffee.surge.sh | github.com/nicolealdurien/catch-up-over-coffee

March 2021

- Member of a 4-person distributed development team building a one-stop website where users can start their morning by catching up on news, viewing the latest stock market quotes, checking out local weather, and more.
- Primary responsibilities included proper project scoping and timeboxing for the team, implementing a fully mobile-responsive layout, developing news page functionality including API consumption/duplicate story removal/filtering stories by topic and source, and creation of in-house JSON documents to pull from for sections of the site without good public APIs.
- Built with Javascript, HTML, and CSS; consumes multiple RESTful APIs.

Professional Work Experience

Emory University Hospital | Medical Technologist II | Atlanta, GA

April 2016 - December 2020

• Performed compatibility testing on patients, donor blood, and bone marrow transplant products to ensure safe transfusions at a 600-bed hospital. Collaborated daily with staff at the Red Cross and other area hospitals to best serve the region's patients.

Reproductive Biology Associates | Medical Technologist/Andrologist | Atlanta, GA

September 2014 – April 2016

• Performed andrological and endocrine testing for potential IVF patients. Guided patients who sought donor sperm through the process of selecting a bank, ordering, and shipping vials to us. Maintained FDA-compliant records for frozen specimens.